Postcards
Marist Archives and Special Collections
Postcards
2.1.7
Marist College
  Box 1599
- Postcards, 2.1.7
  - Africa (local peoples) [John Hinde postcards], undated; 1 (Box 1599)
    - Young Africa; Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 1
    - YOUNG AFRICA: The laughter of the African child is warm and infectious, displaying the gaiety and exuberance so characteristic of Africans. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 1-verso
    - Gathering Coconuts. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 2
    - PALM-FRINGED BEACHES, lapped by warm waters, deserted, and stretching mile after mile, constitute one of Africa's many tourist attractions. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 2-verso
    - Fruit stall; Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 3
    - MOMBASA. The aroma and colour of a typical fruit stall, presenting a wide variety of tropical produce, enchants the passer-by. Printed and Published b John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 3-verso
    - River Scene. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 4
    - RIVER SCENE: The African coast is broken by deltas and lagoons. In these calm waterways river people carry goods tor sale and barter. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 4-verso
    - An African Village. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 5
    - AFRICAN VILLAGE HUTS, fashioned from mud and bark, huddle together in warm neighbourly clusters. The season's grain is kept in large earthen storehouses. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 5-verso
    - El-Molo Fisherman., 6
    - EL MOLO FISHERMAN: One of the world's smallest tribes live on the shores of the 3,500 sq. miles alkaline Lake Rudolf. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 6-verso
    - African Fisherman. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 7
    - FISHERMEN: Africa's waters abound with fish. Fishermen glide down lagoons and rivers, casting nets. Others brave boiling surf in homemade dug-outs. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 7-verso
    - Leather Worker. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 8
    - LEATHER WORKERS produce saddlery, wallets, bags and shoes. All the exquisite design and embroidery is done by men instead of women. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 8-verso
    - Market Women. Photo: E. Ludwig, John Hinde Studios., 9
    - MARKET WOMEN chat with friends and haggle over prices with the buyer. Here one buys peppers, tomatoes, onions, as well as exotic fruits. Photographed, Published and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 9-verso
    - Famous handicraft chests, Zanzibar. Photo: E. Ludwig, John Hinde Studios., 10
    - ZANZIBAR, famous for its cloves, is also famous for various handicrafts and in particular decorated chests. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 10-verso
    - African Market. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 11
    - AFRICAN MARKET: Customers haggle over prices, chat amongst friends and it is here that all local foodstuffs change hands. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 11-verso
    - African Market. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 12
    - AFRICAN MARKET: Customers haggle over prices, chat amongst friends and it is here that all local foodstuffs change hands. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 12-verso
    - Vasco da Gama Street, Mombasa, Kenya., 13
    - VASCO DAGAMA STREET is typical of the narrow streets in the old town and is a reminder of its stormy history. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 13-verso
    - Colourful tribesmen., 14
    - TRIBESMEN in colourful regalia, inhabiting the high ground above the Kavirondo Gulf of Lake Victoria as far as the foot of Mt. Elgon. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 14-verso
    - Deep-sea Angling., 15
    - DEEP-SEA ANGLING: African waters swarm with big-game fish such as blue or black marlin, sail -fish and hammerhead sharks. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 15-verso
    - Flame Tree. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 16
    - AFRICAN FLAME TREE (Sterculia Acerifolia). Known as the " flame of the forest" this tree is a riot of flamboyant red and emerald green. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 16-verso
    - Festival Dancers. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 17
    - DANCING: Harvest-time and religious festivals are occasions for dancing, when the swaying bodies of the men and women display the African's gift for rhythm. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 17-verso
    - Calabash Carver. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 18
    - CARVING decorative designs on sun-ripened gourds is a traditional craft. Originally used as containers, carved calabashes are now popular tourist souvenirs. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 18-verso
    - Milk-maids. Color Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 19
    - MILK MAIDS: Women go to market with their calabashes of skim milk and there sell it to buy the needs of the family. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 19-verso
    - Masai homestead. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 20
    - MASAI: The life of this pastoral nomadic tribe revolves around their cattle, off whose milk and blood they almost entirely live. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. dublin, republic of Ireland., 20-verso
    - Chuka Drummers- Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 21
    - DANCING: Harvest-time and religious festivals are occasions for dancing, when the swaying bodies of the men and women display the African's gift for rhythm. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 21-verso
    - Mother and Child. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 22
    - THE AFRICAN CHILD begins life snuggled in the soft cradle of his mother's back, held by a cloth wrapped around her. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 22-verso
    - Country Girl. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 23
    - COUNTRY GIRL: Some young African girls use antimony mascara to enhance the eyes and for patterning the face and neck with stunning effect. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 23-verso
    - Brass Ware Vendor. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 24
    - BRASS WARE VENDOR: The African's skill in decorative design is seen in the brass bowls offered for sale by this young merchant. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 24-verso
    - The Potter. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 25
    - THE POTTER: The art of pottery is carried on throughout Africa and fulfils the need of the African for water and beer pots. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 25-verso
    - Fruit Vendor. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 26
    - AFRICAN MERCHANTS: African people are natural-born traders. Women operate in local markets and all carry loads of saleable items on their heads. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 26-verso
    - Pounding Grain. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 27
    - POUNDING GRAIN: For centuries African women have pounded their millet, corn, or cassava roots as the first step in preparing the family meal. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 27-verso
    - Market. Photo: E. Ludwig, John Hinde Studios, 28
    - MARKET WOMEN chat with friends and haggle over prices with the buyer. Here one buys peppers, tomatoes, onions. as well as exotic fruits. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 28-verso
    - Town Girl. Photo: E. Ludwig, John Hinde Studios., 29
    - TOWN GIRL: This young lady has cheerfully discarded the traditional dress of her sisters elsewhere in Africa and dashingly flaunts western-style clothes. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 29-verso
    - Masai woman. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 30
    - MASAI WOMAN: A pastoral nomadic tribe. The women shave their heads and are adorned by enormous beaded ear and neck ornaments. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 30-verso
    - Smiling Girl. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 31
    - AFRICAN WOMEN: Facial markings are a common feature among the women of Africa. From childhood they skilfully carry heavy loads on their heads. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 31-verso
    - High Fashion. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 32
    - HIGH FASHION: African women wear innumerable hair styles. Usually the hair is greased, combed, tightly braided and then decorated, sometimes with beads or shells. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 32-verso
    - Masai Woman., 33
    - MASAI WOMAN: A pastoral nomadic tribe. The women shave their heads and are adorned by enormous beaded ear and neck ornaments. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 33-verso
    - Turkana tribesman., 34
    - TURKANA TRIBE of North-West Kenya are cattle people and strong individualists. The men have very elaborate hair styles which are regularly reset. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 34-verso
    - Chuka Drummer. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 35
    - DANCING: Harvest-time and religious festivals are occasions for dancing, when the swaying bodies of the men and women display the African's gift for rhythm. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 35-verso
    - Turkana Woman., 36
    - TURKANA of Northwest Kenya: the women of Turkana society have a high status and dress in superb bead and shell ornaments. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 36-verso
    - Abaluhya tribesman, 37
    - ABALUHYA TRIBE is the collective name given to the large group of Bantu-speaking people living above the Kavirondo Gulf of Lake Victoria. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 37-verso
    - Masai herdboy and his dog. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 38
    - MASAI: The life of this pastoral nomadic tribe revolves around their cattle, off whose milk and blood they almost entirely live. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 38-verso
    - Masai Elder. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 39
    - MASAI: The life of this pastoral nomadic tribe revolves around their cattle, off whose milk and blood they almost entirely live. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 39-verso
    - Masai woman. Colour Photo byJohn Hinde, F.R.P.S., 40
    - MASAI WOMAN: A pastoral nomadic tribe. The women shave their heads and are adorned by enormous beaded ear and neck ornaments. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 40-verso
    - Ebony Carver. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 41
    - WOOD-CARVING illustrates in profusion and detail the life of the African people. Skilled craftsmen with crude tools attain remarkably fine finishes. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 41-verso
    - African Warrior. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.S.P., 42
    - AFRICA'S WARRIORS are fearless fighters and hunters. Tribesmen have to prove their courage and strength before being given the responsibilities of manhood. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 42-verso
    - African Fisherman. Photo: E. Ludwig, John Hinde Studios., 43
    - FISHERMEN glide silently over the water, one man poling while the other casts his hawk-net to draw in the catch. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 43-verso
    - Sheltered Bay. Photo: E. Ludwig, John Hinde Studios., 44
    - AFRICA'S COASTLINE offers an endless variety of wonderful beaches, with here and there a sheltered cove or mile upon mile of deserted beaches. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 44-verso
  - Africa (tourists) [John Hinde postcards], undated; 2 (Box 1599)
    - Ngorongoro Crater, Tanzania. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 1
    - NGORONGORO CRATER has been described as the "Garden of Eden". lts 102 sq. miles floor is the home of thousands of wild animals. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 1-verso
    - Palm-fringed Beach. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 2
    - PALM-FRINGED BEACHES, lapped by warm waters, deserted, and stretching mile after mile, constitute one of Africa's many tourist attractions. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 2-verso
    - Photographic Safari, East Africa. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 3
    - EAST AFRICA, with its vast game lands, provides amateur and professional photographers alike with exciting subject material demanding skill and patience. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 3-verso
  - Africa (buildings) [John Hinde postcards], undated; 3 (Box 1599)
    - Dar es Salaam Harbour, Tanzania. Colour Photo by john Hinde, F.R.P.S., 1
    - DARES SALAAM, the ''haven of peace", is the seaside capital and principal port of Tanzania with a population of approximately 250,000. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 1-verso
    - Lutheran Church, Dar es Salaam, Tanzania. Colour Photo by john Hinde, F.R.P.S., 2
    - THE LUTHERAN CHURCH, completed in 1907, is one of the landmarks along the beautiful Dar es Salaam seafront. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 2-verso
    - The Kilimanjaro Hotel, Dar es Salaam, Tanzania. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 3
    - THE KILIMANJARO is one of East Africa's most luxurious hotels. This spacious ten-storey building with 200 beds offers comfort in delightful surroundings. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 3-verso
    - Hindu Temple, Mombasa, Kenya., 4
    - THIS HINDU TEMPLE is comparatively new and renowned for its brilliantly painted doors. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 4-verso
    - Norfolk Hotel, Nairobi, Kenva. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 5
    - NORFOLK HOTEL, of international standard, is within five minutes walk of the city centre, offering excellent cuisine, leisurely atmosphere and a swimming pool. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 5-verso
    - Kenyatta Avenue, Nairobi. Photo: E. Ludwig, John Hinde Studios., 6
    - NAIROBI, Kenya's sunny capital, is the only modern city in within the lion's roar and the starting point for adventure in East Africa. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 6-verso
    - Parliament Buildings, Nairobi, Kenya. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 7
    - PARLIAMENT BUILDINGS: Dominated by a striking clock tower, these buildings are one of the city's best examples of modern architecture. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 7-verso
    - Oceanic Hotel, Mombasa, Kenya. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 8
    - OCEANIC HOTEL, of international standard, has air-conditioned dining room and cocktail bar and a swimming pool. It is situated 1 mile from the town centre. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 8-verso
    - Hotel Ambassadeur, Nairobi, Kenya. Colour Photo by John Hinde F.R.P.S., 9
    - HOTEL AMBASSADEUR, one of East Africa 's leading luxury hotels of international standard, is specially noted for its courteous and efficient personal service. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 9-verso
    - New Stanley Hilton Hotel, Nairobi, Kenya. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F. R.P.S., 10
    - NEW STANLEY HILTON HOTEL, of international standard, is situated in the centre of Nairobi offering most comfortable accommodation and excellent cuisine. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 10-verso
    - Panafric Hotel, Nairobi, Kenya. ColourPhoto by John Hilde F.R.P.S., 11
    - PANAFRIC HOTEL offers first class accommodation and facilities of international standard with superb cuisine and service, together with a new luxury swimming pool. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 11-verso
    - Vasco da Gama Memorial, Malindi, Kenya., 12
    - MALINDI was subjugated by the Portuguese in the 16th and 17th centuries and they established their headquarters here. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 12-verso
  - Africa (seascapes and landscapes) [John Hinde postcards], undated; 4 (Box 1599)
    - Mount Kilimanjaro. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 1
    - MOUNT KILIMANJARO (19,340 feet) Africa's highest mountain, permanently snowcapped. An extinct volcano offering a challenge to the climber. Usually cloud free in January. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 1-verso
    - Ngorongoro Crater, Tanzania. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 2
    - NGORONGORO CRATER has been described as the " Garden of Eden". Its 102 sq. miles floor is the home of thousands of wild animals. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 2-verso
    - Nyali Floating Bridge, Mombasa, Kenya. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 3
    - NYALI FLOATING BRIDGE links the island to the north side of the mainland where popular resorts provide good hotels and splendid beaches. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic., 3-verso
    - Likoni Ferry, Mombasa, Kenya. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 4
    - LIKONI FERRY links the southern mainland with the colourful tiny island, redolent with stormy history and traditionally called the "Island of War". Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co,. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 4-verso
    - Dar es Salaam Harbour, Tanzania. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 5
    - DAR ES SALAAM HARBOUR, with deep-water berths, a bulk oil jetty and extensive facilities, handles over 1,200,000 tons of cargo annually. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabiteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland, 5-verso
    - Dar es Salaam Harbour, Tanzania. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 6
    - DAR ES SALAAM HARBOUR showing the departure of a large seagoing vessel and the ferry which links the city with Kigamboni. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limted, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 6-verso
    - The beach, Malindi, Kenya. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 7
    - MALINDI, the holidaymaker's paradise on East Africa's coast, is a wonderland for the skilled scuba diver and all water sports. Rinted and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 7-verso
    - Silversands Holiday Camp, Malindi, Kenya. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 8
    - SILVERSANDS HOLIDAY CAMP is situated on Kenya's 300 mile Indian Ocean coast with warm crystal clear water and unspoilt palm-fringed beaches. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabonteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 8-verso
    - Fort Jesus, Kenya. Colour Photo by John Hindi, F.R.P.S., 9
    - FORT JESUS, built by the Portuguese at the end of the 16th Century, is now a museum housing relics of the past. Printed and Published by Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 9-verso
  - Africa (birds) [John Hinde postcards], undated; 5 (Box 1599)
    - Speke's Weavers. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 1
    - SPEKE'S WEAVERS (Pioceus spekei) are among the world's best nest builders and their ball-like nests are ingeniously made of woven grass. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, CO. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 1-verso
    - Greater Flamingo and chick., 2
    - GREATER FLAMINGO (Phoenicopterus ruber roseus). Breed in large colonies building a rough mud nest 12" high on which they lay one egg. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely, Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 2-verso
    - White-backed Vultures and Jackal. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 3
    - WHITE-BACKED VULTURE (Pseudogyps africanus). After a 'kill' vultures gorge themselves. Other scavengers like the Black-backed Jackal (Canis mesomelas) join in. Photographed, Printed, and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland, 3-verso
    - Greater Flamingoes. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 4
    - GREATER FLAMINGOES (Phoenicopterus ruber). Feed on alkaline lakes. Bills are specially adapted to extract minute organisms from the water, the bill is held upside-down when feeding. Printed, and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 4-verso
    - Greater Flamingoes and Pelicans. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 5
    - GREATER FLAMINGOES (Phoenicopterus ruber). Feed on alkaline lakes. Bills are specially adapted to extract minute organisms from the water, the bill is held upside-down when feeding. Printed, and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 5-verso
    - Greater Flamingoes. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 6
    - GREATER FLAMINGOES (Phoenicopterus ruber). Feed on alkaline lakes. Bills are specially adapted to extract minute organisms from the water, the bill is held upside-down when feeding. Printed, and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 6-verso
    - Greater Flamingoes. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 7
    - GREATER FLAMINGOES (Phoenicopterus ruber). Feed on alkaline lakes. Bills are specially adapted to extract minute organisms from the water, the bill is held upside-down when feeding. Printed, and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 7-verso